{
  "Experiment 1: Measurement of total protein content in the given sample": [
    {
      "question": "In Biuret's reaction, copper reacts with ----- atoms of the peptides to form a cuprous complex?",
      "options": [
        "Carbon atoms of the carboxyl group",
        "Nitrogen atoms of peptides",
        "Hydroxide ion",
        "Sulphur atoms of the methionine and cysteine"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Nitrogen atoms of peptides"
    },
    {
      "question": "To test for protein, a food sample must first be",
      "options": [
        "Ground up in water",
        "Ground up in sodium hydroxide",
        "Added to ethanol and mixed",
        "Ground up in ethanol"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Ground up in water"
    },
    {
      "question": "For the Biurate reaction to occur, the copper sulphate has to be _____",
      "options": [
        "Neutral",
        "None",
        "Alkaline",
        "Acidic"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Alkaline"
    }
  ],
  "Experiment 2: Measurement of glucose concentration in the given sample": [
    {
      "question": "Glucose in urine is quantified by oxidation to",
      "options": [
        "Aldehyde group",
        "Gluconic acid",
        "phosphomolybdic acid",
        "Glucose"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Gluconic acid"
    },
    {
      "question": "In GOD/POD method, ------------ is the oxidising agent and ---------- produces red coloration.",
      "options": [
        "Glucose oxidase, peroxidase",
        "Peroxidase, Gluconic acid",
        "Gluconic acid, Peroxidase",
        "Peroxidase, Glucose oxidase"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Glucose oxidase, peroxidase"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which optical form of glucose is naturally present and readily absorbed by our body",
      "options": [
        "D-Glucose",
        "L-Glucose",
        "Both",
        "None"
      ],
      "correct_option": "D-Glucose"
    },
    {
      "question": "D-form of glucose is also known as _______________.",
      "options": [
        "None",
        "Galactose",
        "Dextrose",
        "Fructose"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Dextrose"
    }
  ],
  "Experiment 3: Measurement of mitotic index and duration of mitosis in the given plant tissue": [
    {
      "question": "Chromosomes start separating at which stage of mitosis",
      "options": [
        "Early anaphase",
        "Early telophase",
        "Late metaphase",
        "Early metaphase"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Early anaphase"
    },
    {
      "question": "Chromosomes are arranged along the equatorial plate during ____",
      "options": [
        "Telophase",
        "Anaphase",
        "Prophase",
        "Metaphase"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Metaphase"
    },
    {
      "question": "During which phase does the DNA make a copy of itself?",
      "options": [
        "prophase",
        "anaphase",
        "metaphase",
        "interphase"
      ],
      "correct_option": "interphase"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the cell cycle, Mitotic phase occurs after the",
      "options": [
        "S phase",
        "G2 phase",
        "G1 phase",
        "G0 phase"
      ],
      "correct_option": "G2 phase"
    },
    {
      "question": "The event which does not occur during interphase, is",
      "options": [
        "Organelles replication",
        "DNA replication",
        "Protein Synthesis",
        "Chromatin condenses"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Chromatin condenses"
    },
    {
      "question": "The frequency of a mitotic cell when there are 136 mitotic cells in a culture of 300 cells is:",
      "options": [
        "0.45",
        "0.90",
        "2.20",
        "136"
      ],
      "correct_option": "0.45"
    },
    {
      "question": "Match the stages of mitosis",
      "options": [
        "Anaphase → chromosomes move towards the opposite poles, Telophase → nuclear membranes are formed again, Interphase → DNA replication, Metaphase → equatorial plane, Prophase → Replication of centrosome"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Anaphase → chromosomes move towards the opposite poles, Telophase → nuclear membranes are formed again, Interphase → DNA replication, Metaphase → equatorial plane, Prophase → Replication of centrosome"
    },
    {
      "question": "______ are found in animal cells but not in that of higher plants",
      "options": [
        "Spindle fibres",
        "Kinetochores",
        "Centrioles",
        "Microtubules"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Centrioles"
    }
  ],
  "Experiment 4: a. Measurement of Haemoglobin content in human blood. b. Determination of ABO-Rh Blood Typing": [
    {
      "question": "Each hemoglobin molecule binds to how many divalent iron (Fe) of each porphyrin unit?",
      "options": [
        "4",
        "1",
        "3",
        "2"
      ],
      "correct_option": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "In normal body conditions, the percentage of haemoglobin in red blood cells is -----",
      "options": [
        "Variable",
        "None of the above",
        "Fluctuating",
        "Constant"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Constant"
    },
    {
      "question": "If one of your parents is blood type A and the other is blood type B, which of the following blood types would you likely be?",
      "options": [
        "either A, B, AB or O",
        "B",
        "O",
        "A"
      ],
      "correct_option": "either A, B, AB or O"
    },
    {
      "question": "agglutinogens are antigenic substances present in blood cells, bacteria, etc., which stimulates the formation of an agglutinin in blood serum.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct_option": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is formed when HCl is added to blood haemoglobin?",
      "options": [
        "Hemanicic acid",
        "Nucleic acid",
        "Hemic acid",
        "Hematinic acid"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Hematinic acid"
    },
    {
      "question": "Match the following: ABO blood group was discovered by, AB blood group is the universal, Rh factor was discovered by",
      "options": [
        "K Landsteiner, recipient, K Landsteiner and S Weiener"
      ],
      "correct_option": "K Landsteiner, recipient, K Landsteiner and S Weiener"
    },
    {
      "question": "If a sample of blood contains A agglutinogen and anti B agglutinin what will be the blood group?",
      "options": [
        "O",
        "B",
        "AB",
        "A"
      ],
      "correct_option": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "Erythroblastosis fetalis happens _______",
      "options": [
        "When the mother is Rh negative and the child is Rh negative",
        "When mother is Rh positive and the child is Rh negative",
        "When mother is Rh negative and the child is Rh positive",
        "When the mother is Rh positive and the child is also Rh positive"
      ],
      "correct_option": "When mother is Rh negative and the child is Rh positive"
    }
  ],
  "Experiment 10: Measurement of Blood Pressure": [
    {
      "question": "If a person has a systolic reading of 118 and a diastolic reading of 78, what will be that person's pulse pressure?",
      "options": [
        "78/118",
        "118/78",
        "98",
        "40"
      ],
      "correct_option": "40"
    },
    {
      "question": "When does the sound becomes muffled and disappear while measuring blood pressure?",
      "options": [
        "when pressure decreases in the vessel",
        "when the heart rate increase",
        "when pressure increases in the vessel",
        "when the heart rate decreases"
      ],
      "correct_option": "when pressure decreases in the vessel"
    },
    {
      "question": "What can you do to control high blood pressure?",
      "options": [
        "All",
        "Avoid smoking",
        "Stress Management",
        "Avoid alcohol"
      ],
      "correct_option": "All"
    },
    {
      "question": "Resistance to blood flow depends on:",
      "options": [
        "None",
        "Vessel radius",
        "Both Vessel length and radius",
        "Vessel Length"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Both Vessel length and radius"
    },
    {
      "question": "Systolic pressure is peak pressure in arteries, when the ventricles are",
      "options": [
        "contracting",
        "expanding",
        "relaxed",
        "All"
      ],
      "correct_option": "contracting"
    },
    {
      "question": "The amount of blood pumped out from the heart with each contraction is called",
      "options": [
        "heart rate",
        "stroke volume",
        "flow rate",
        "mean blood pressure"
      ],
      "correct_option": "stroke volume"
    },
    {
      "question": "High blood pressure puts you at risk for which of the following?",
      "options": [
        "Heart disease",
        "All",
        "Kidney disease",
        "Stroke"
      ],
      "correct_option": "All"
    },
    {
      "question": "Increased ---------- levels lead to damages of the endothelium in blood vessels:",
      "options": [
        "Homocystein",
        "Plasmalipoprotein",
        "Cholesterol",
        "Triglycerides"
      ],
      "correct_option": "Homocystein"
    },
    {
      "question": "3:2:1 ratio can be used a diagnostic tool which refers to",
      "options": [
        "pulse pressure: systolic: diastolic",
        "systolic: diastolic: pulse pressure",
        "pulse pressure: diastolic: systolic",
        "systolic: pulse pressure: diastolic"
      ],
      "correct_option": "systolic: diastolic: pulse pressure"
    }
  ],
  "Experiment 12: Computational annotation of nucleic acids and proteins": [
    {
      "question": "Choose the correct expansion for EMBOSS:",
      "options": [
        "European Microbiology Biology Open Software Suite",
        "European Molecular Biology Open Software System",
        "European Molecular Biology Open Software Suite",
        "European Microbiology Biology Open Software System"
      ],
      "correct_option": "European Molecular Biology Open Software Suite"
    }
  ]
}
